{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Brakes","incorrectAnswers":["Steering Wheel","Engine","Exhaust Pipe"],"question":"In a car, what might be disc or drum?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Syracuse ","incorrectAnswers":["Albany","Uticer","Ithaca"],"question":"Which port of Sicily shares its name with a city in New York State?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Napoleon","incorrectAnswers":["Charlemagne","De Gaulle","Joan of Arc"],"question":"Which French Ruler Was Finally Defeated In 1815?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Austria-Hungary","Bulgaria"],"question":"Which of the following was NOT one of the Ottoman Empire's major allies during World War I?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Cure","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Snow Patrol"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Disintegration'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Enid Blyton","incorrectAnswers":["J. R. R. Tolkien","Lewis Carroll","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Famous Five'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Best a Man Can Get","incorrectAnswers":["Quality never goes out of style","Easy, breezy, beautiful….","Maybe she's born with it"],"question":"Which marketing slogan would you associate with Gillette?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A Hogshead","incorrectAnswers":["An Alekeg","A Bogteen","A Grond"],"question":"Which archaic imperial unit of measure is equivalent to 54 gallons?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Agatha Christie","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Louis Stevenson","Charles Dickens","Lewis Carroll"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Partners in Crime'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Niger","incorrectAnswers":["Congo","Zaïre","Benue"],"question":"Name the longest river in Nigeria.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sigourney Weaver","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Bancroft","Angela Lansbury","Katharine Hepburn"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Ellen Ripley in Alien?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Austroasiatic","Japonic"],"question":"The language 'North Levantine Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tehran","incorrectAnswers":["Isfahan","Shiraz","Tabriz"],"question":"What is the capital of Iran?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Holy Roman Empire","incorrectAnswers":["The Roman Empire","Napoleon's French Empire","The German Empire"],"question":"What did Nazi Germany refer to as The First Reich?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"San Jose","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra la Vella","Port of Spain","Majuro"],"question":"What is the capital city of Costa Rica?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Ugly American","incorrectAnswers":["The Quiet American","The Americanization of Emily","An American in Vietnam"],"question":"Which 1963 drama features Marlon Brando as the U.S. Ambassador to an Asian country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"affricative","incorrectAnswers":["nasal","plosive","approximant"],"question":"In phonetics, the j in 'juice' is an example of what kind of sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belize","incorrectAnswers":["El Salvador","Honduras","Nicaragua"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Mexico?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Schnapps","incorrectAnswers":["Rakia","Tequila","Mama Juana"],"question":"Which of these is a popular drink in Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Breathless","incorrectAnswers":["The 400 Blows","Jules and Jim","Contempt"],"question":"Which 1959 French New Wave film, with a story provided by Truffaut, features Belmondo as a hoodlum who kills a cop?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tomato juice","incorrectAnswers":["Lemonade","Iced tea","Milk"],"question":"What is the state beverage of Ohio?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Apparent Magnitude","incorrectAnswers":["Apparent Luminosity","Apparent Intensity","Apparent Radiance"],"question":"In astronomy, what is the term for the measurement of the brightness of stars?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ares","incorrectAnswers":["Athena","Hephaestus","Zeus"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman god Mars?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Aves","incorrectAnswers":["Birdilia","Flowana","Aerilys"],"question":"In the animal kingdom, if reptiles are in class reptilia, then birds are in class ____?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Netherlands","incorrectAnswers":["France","Poland","Turkey"],"question":"From what country does Advocaat originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James and the Giant Peach","incorrectAnswers":["John and the Giant Apple","Jack and the Giant Pear","Jonah and the Giant Pineapple"],"question":"In which book did Roald Dahl tell the story of a boy's adventure in a giant piece of fruit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Bhutan","Central America"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Döner Kebab?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mogadishu","incorrectAnswers":["Tashkent","Dushanbe","Majuro"],"question":"What is the capital city of Somalia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Texas","incorrectAnswers":["Florida","Michigan","California"],"question":"In which US state is the Houston Space Centre?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"San Francisco 49ers","incorrectAnswers":["San Francisco Jaguars","San Francisco Pistons","San Francisco Predators"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in San Francisco?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New York Knicks","incorrectAnswers":["New York 76ers","New York Penguins","New York Eagles"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in New York?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The flamingo","incorrectAnswers":["The pelican","The stork","The heron"],"question":"What is the name of the bird whose scientific name is Phoenicopterus ruber roseus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bamako","incorrectAnswers":["Lomé","Managua","Zagreb"],"question":"What is the capital city of Mali?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2009","incorrectAnswers":["2007","2011","2013"],"question":"In which year was Up first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Greece","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Spain","Egypt"],"question":"Which country was served by Olympic Airlines?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Paris","incorrectAnswers":["Stockholm","Berlin","Leipzig"],"question":"Which of these cities is in France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Two ","incorrectAnswers":["Five","Four","Three"],"question":"How many standard bottles of champagne are in a magnum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jack Nicholson","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Shaw","James Stewart","Harrison Ford"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Randle Patrick McMurphy in One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Bob Cratchit","incorrectAnswers":["Billy Catchit","Norman Patchit","Gregory Snatchit"],"question":"What is the name of Tiny Tim's father in the story, 'A Christmas Carol'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Wind","incorrectAnswers":["Percussion","String","Keyboard"],"question":"What type of instrument is a harmonica?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Poland","Albania","Kazakhstan"],"question":"Bern is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Marlon Brando","incorrectAnswers":["Anthony Perkins","Bruce Willis","Humphrey Bogart"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Terry Malloy in On the Waterfront?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Hi-hat","incorrectAnswers":["Snare","Ride cymbals","Tom-tom"],"question":"What is the name of the pair of cymbals on a drum kit controlled by a foot pedal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Terminator","incorrectAnswers":["RoboCop","Aliens","Predator"],"question":"Which movie from 1984 features the line 'It doesn't feel pity, or remorse, or fear. And it absolutely will not stop... ever, until you are dead!'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I’m already pregnant. So, what other shenanigans could I get myself into?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"This is Sparta!\"","\"Sawyer, you're going out a youngster, but you've t to come back a star!\"","\"You shall not pass!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Juno'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"94","incorrectAnswers":["97","89","91"],"question":"What is the result of the mathematical operation obtained by subtracting the number of Snow White's dwarfs from the original title number of 'Disney Dalmatians'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Milwaukee Bucks","incorrectAnswers":["Milwaukee Heat","Milwaukee Reds","Milwaukee Pirates"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Milwaukee?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Larva","incorrectAnswers":["Bulba","Curla","Meta"],"question":"The four stages in the lifecycle of an insect are: egg, adult, pupa, and ________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Annex","incorrectAnswers":["Appendix","Addendum","Supplement"],"question":"What is the word for an auxiliary building near the main one?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Aphrodite","incorrectAnswers":["Athena","Hera","Minerva"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the roman god Venus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Becherovka","incorrectAnswers":["Sangria","Seco Herrerano","Koskenkorva Viina"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with The Czech Republic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Boar","incorrectAnswers":["A Drone","A Macho","A Tom"],"question":"What is a male panda known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"European Robin","incorrectAnswers":["African Hawk","Albatross ","Grey Pigeon "],"question":"Which garden bird is famous for their red breast and beady eyes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Laura Dern","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Scarlett Johansson","Florence Pugh"],"question":"Who won the 2019 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Nora Fanshaw in Marriage Story?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"17th century","incorrectAnswers":["18th century","19th century","20th century"],"question":"In which century did the Thirty Years' War take place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Nile","incorrectAnswers":["The Yangtze","The Ganges","The Mississippi"],"question":"What river is the Temple of Karnak near?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1985","incorrectAnswers":["1970","1975","1980"],"question":"In which year was Back to the Future first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["China","Vietnam","India"],"question":"Which country uses the 'yen' for currency?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Copper and Zinc","incorrectAnswers":["Iron and Bronze","Silver and Steel","Tin and Gold"],"question":"Which two metals make up brass?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Whale","incorrectAnswers":["Echnaton","Yeti","Aliens"],"question":"In the novel Moby Dick, what do Ahab and Ishmael encounter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Carbon","incorrectAnswers":["Oxygen","Hydrogen","Gold"],"question":"Coal is composed of which element?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"drug dosage","incorrectAnswers":["origin of life","diseases of stomach and intestines","poisons"],"question":"What is Posology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ursula K. Le Guin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Word for World Is Forest'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Morocco","incorrectAnswers":["Romania","Zambia","Iraq"],"question":"Rabat is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Brutus","incorrectAnswers":["Puck","Hermia","Oberon"],"question":"Which of the following characters does not appear in Shakespeare's 'A Midsummer Night's Dream'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Soccer","Badminton","Volleyball"],"question":"Within Which Sport Might You Encounter The Cyclops System?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Jill","incorrectAnswers":["A Jenny","A Cow","A Soar"],"question":"A female ferret is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"1984","incorrectAnswers":["1986","1988","1990"],"question":"In what year was Band-Aid's Do They Know It's Christmas the UK Christmas chart-topping record?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sri Lanka","incorrectAnswers":["India","Nepal","Pakistan"],"question":"Ceylon officially became which country on May 22, 1972?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jacques-Louis David","incorrectAnswers":["Vincent van Gogh","Édouard Manet","Pierre-Auguste Renoir"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Portrait of Madame Recamier\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Are you not entertained?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Nobody puts Baby in a corner.\"","\"La-dee-da, la-dee-da.\"","\"I'll have what she's having.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Gladiator'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Hob","A Cob","A Billy"],"question":"What would you call a male manatee?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Buck","incorrectAnswers":["A Stallion","A Dog","A Boar"],"question":"A male rabbit is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Antarctica","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","Asia","South America"],"question":"What continent is the Bellingshausen Sea next to? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"One","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Eight","Ten"],"question":"In Spanish, what is the meaning of the word 'uno'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Kra–Dai","Sino-Tibetan","Austroasiatic"],"question":"The language 'Northern Pashto' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Moschino","incorrectAnswers":["Valentino","Givenchy","Prada"],"question":"Which of the following fashion houses is famous for its colorful, eccentric designs, often made with unusual materials?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"society","incorrectAnswers":["bones","the preparation of books and manuscripts","nematodes"],"question":"What is Sociology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"carbon copy","incorrectAnswers":["clear cut","courtesy confirmation","cordially confirm"],"question":"What does the abbreviation cc: near the bottom of a letter mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Afghanistan","incorrectAnswers":["Kyrgyzstan","Bosnia and Herzegovina","Australia"],"question":"Which of these countries has black on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Volkswagen","BMW","Porsche"],"question":"Which motoring brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'Go Further'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Four","incorrectAnswers":["Five","Six","Two"],"question":"What does the word 'vier' mean in Dutch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chile","incorrectAnswers":["Argentina","Mexico","Brazil"],"question":"Which of these countries is between Bolivia and the Pacific Ocean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","France","Canada"],"question":"Which country was suspended from the G8 in 2014?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bengali","incorrectAnswers":["Quechua","Portuguese","Swahili"],"question":"Which of these languages would you find spoken in India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Vladimir Nabokov","incorrectAnswers":["Ayn Rand","Kurt Vonnegut","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Annotated Lolita (1991 Vintage Books ed.)'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"War of the Worlds","incorrectAnswers":["The Time Machine","1984","The Invisible Man"],"question":"What was the title of the most famous broadcast of \"The Mercury Theater on the Air,\" which aired on October 30, 1938 and caused panic across the United States?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"New Radicals","incorrectAnswers":["The Proclaimers","Vicki Lawrence","Brownsville Station"],"question":"'You Get What You Give' was a one hit wonder in 1999 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ursula K. Le Guin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Hainish Cycle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Mongolia","Nigeria","Angola"],"question":"In what country do people speak the Language they call Nihongo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Schindler's List","incorrectAnswers":["The Fugitive","In the Name of the Father","The Piano"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1993?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jared Leto","incorrectAnswers":["Peter Cushing","Kenneth Branagh","Luke Evans"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including Suicide Squad and Requiem for a Dream?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Hudson Bay","incorrectAnswers":["Erie Bay","Superior Bay","Georgian Bay"],"question":"James Bay, located in Ontario and Quebec, is the southern arm of which larger bay?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Michael Crichton","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Stephen Chbosky","David Lynch"],"question":"Which best selling American writer wrote and directed the sci-fi film Westworld?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Matthew McConaughey","incorrectAnswers":["Christian Bale","Bruce Dern","Leonardo DiCaprio"],"question":"Who won the 2013 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Ron Woodroof in Dallas Buyers Club?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Macrosmatic","incorrectAnswers":["Nudiustertian","Conjubilant","Gubbins"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'having a good sense of smell'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Buffalo Sabres","incorrectAnswers":["Buffalo Colts","Buffalo Dynamo","Buffalo Packers"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Buffalo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Aftermath'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The nature of knowledge","incorrectAnswers":["Mind-altering drugs","Characterizing criminals","The climate"],"question":"What is Epistemology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},